DARREN W. DUNNE

Email: darrenwdunne@gmail.com (919) 524-8451 LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/darrenwdunne Web: http://dwdunne.com

FRONT END DEVELOPER

I am **dedicated to Front End Development and how it affects Users** - constantly striving to understand User's goals, challenges, frustrations, and even the fears they have interfacing with the software we create for them.

In my career in software development, **I've worn many hats**: Programmer, Designer, Scrum Master, UI Development Lead, Chief Programmer, and Software Development Release Manager. These roles have allowed me to experience and influence the complete software development lifecycle in several high-profile products.

From Requirements Analysis to UX and UI Design to Development to Project and Release Management, I consistently strive to focus on the needs of the User.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Development Release Manager

IBM | RTP, NC | 2012 - Present

Managed 2 development teams simultaneously with 18 members in 4 countries for the Tivoli Business Service Manager (TBSM), Tivoli Netcool/Impact and Netcool Operations Insight (NOI) products.

- Introduced and championed Agile Development to the development teams, reducing the time to deliver new releases by 80% (from 18 months to only 3 months).
- Led the effort to reduce the technical debt (defect backlog) by at least 95%, from over 200 outstanding defects typically carried release-to-release to now less than 10.
- Pioneered the implementation of Internationalization (I18N) and Accessibility (A11Y) in each product, achieving 100% capability in both areas.
- Embedded QA and Pubs personnel into the Agile scrums. This helped to reduce the number of defects found in the field by at least 30%, and dramatically improved morale, eliminating the "us vs. them" feelings that had developed over the years.

Chief Programmer - Senior Software Engineer

IBM | RTP, NC | 2006 - 2012

Led 26 programmers in the design, development and release of 4 major multi-year releases of Impact and TBSM, delivering all releases on schedule, with all quality targets achieved.

- Served as Lead of the Scrum of Scrums for 4 separate Scrum teams (Front End, Back End, Install and Tools), identifying, managing and resolving all cross-scrum dependencies.
- Volunteered to assume all Project Management responsibilities for 6 months, after a PM reorganization, and got both projects back on schedule and delivered according to plan.
- Owned the repository of 1.6 million lines of code, responsible for approving all pull requests.
- Established Continuous Development, automating builds and increasing their frequency from once a week to 4 times a day, dramatically improving the time to identify and resolve defects.

Front End Development Team Lead

IBM | RTP, NC | 2001 - 2006

Led 12 developers in the design and implementation of a new cross-platform Java-based user interface for TBSM.

- Instituted customer reviews and usability testing for proposed new features and incorporated the feedback into the designs.
- Introduced UI Design and UX methodologies to release management and implemented it in the development teams.

Front End Developer

IBM | RTP, NC | 1996 - 2001

- Designed and implemented the UIs for SystemView and Global Enterprise Manager.
- Developed the strategy and instrumented 100% of the UI to enable automated verification.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: JavaScript, Java, HTML, HTML5, C, C++

Technologies: CSS, ¡Query, Angular.js, Bootstrap, Sass

Development Tools: Git, GitHub, Eclipse, Ant, Rational Application Developer (RAD), Rational Team Concert (RTC),

Rational AppScan, Grunt, Gulp, Microsoft Project, Microsoft Office

Operating Systems: UNIX, Windows, Mac OS X

EDUCATION

BS Computer Science - Southern Methodist University (SMU) - Dallas, TX